## Ogunlolu, Abigail Ajoke

Address: Lagos, Nigeria. Phone No: +2348142312641
LinkedIn: Abigail Ogunlolu
Email: ogunloluajoke@gmail.com

Porfolio: aogunlolu.netlify.app GitHub: aogunlolu.github

### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I am a seasoned Accountant with over four years of professional experience, complemented by a keen ap;tude for Financial Technologies focused on delivering inven;ve solu;ons within the realm of accoun;ng.

Throughout my career, I have excelled in roles involving Receivables analysis, Payables management, Reconcilia; on, Financial Statement prepara; on, Data analysis, and even Web development. My diverse skill set encompasses proficiency in various technologies, including Excel, SQL, Tableau, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Tailwind CSS, React.js, Git, and GitHub, which I have strategically employed to consistently achieve outstanding results.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

**AXA Mansard Health Insurance.** 

84B Ozumba Mbadiwe. Victoria Island, Lagos.

FEB 2019-SEPT 2022 CREDIT

### **CONTROL OFFICER:**

### Mar 2021- SEPT 2022

- During my tenure, I prepared Trade Receivable, Other debtors, and Account payables schedules, contributed to automa;ng Receivables and Payables Accounts by collabora;ng with SoPware Developers, performed analy;cal procedures on accoun;ng variances, assisted in preparing Management reports, and successfully recovered over 40 Million Naira declared as bad debt in 2021.
- I ac;vely contributed to budget prepara;on, managed NHIS Schedule and remiVance, assisted in preparing monthly, quarterly, and annual financial reports, and effec;vely escalated outstanding receivables to team members and the sales unit.

### SETTLEMENT OFFICER:

Feb 2019- Feb 2021

- Performed various key responsibili;es, including analyzing and pos;ng journals into appropriate ledgers, conduc;ng thorough reviews and reconcilia;ons of all AXA Mansard HMO Accounts, and me;culously reconciling data and reports to resolve discrepancies between bank and ledger. Addi;onally, I took charge of assembling the annual audit informa;on for external auditors, and I successfully liaised with Account officers from various Accounts/Banks operated by AXA Mansard HMO.
- Moreover, I efficiently handled clerical du;es such as filing, remiVance of WHT and VAT, preparing memos and request leVers, as well as handling scanning and photocopying tasks. As part of my role, I diligently reviewed month-end close reports, and when necessary, promptly escalated any problems detected for swiP resolu;on.

Lastly, I ensured me; culous review of all ledgers to maintain accurate and up-to-date financial records.

# ST JOHN'S SCHOOLS, IKORODO ROAD PALMGROOVE. July 2018- Jan 2019 ACCOUNT OFFICER / ADMINSTRATOR

 Ac; vely contributed to various financial tasks, including preparing accurate financial records and maintaining general ledger accounts. I diligently reviewed bank statements on a monthly basis to ensure accuracy and iden; fy any discrepancies, efficiently managed staff payrolls, ensuring; mely and accurate processing of payments. Addi; onally, I priori; zed data security by comple; ng regular database backups and maintaining strict confiden; ality of sensi; ve informa; on.

### OFFICE OF THE AUDITOR GENERAL.

SECRETARIAT, IBADAN. OYO STATE.

2015 / 2017-2018 NYSC /

### **INTERNSHIP**

- Checked documenta; on suppor; ng accoun; ng balances and classes of transac; on with a third party.
- Checked and confirmed account receivable and other accounts with third par;es.
- Performed analy;cal procedures on expected and unexpected variance in accoun;ng balances or classes of transac;on.

PERSONAL DETAILS Sex: Female Na\onality:

Nigerian

EDUCATION Award/Ins\tu\on Year

PGD COMPUTER SCIENCE. 2022- 2023

BABCOCK UNIVERSITY ILISAN-REMO, OGUN STATE.

BSc. ACCOUNTING 2013-2016

LES COURS SONOU UNIVERSITY COTONOU. REPUBLIC OF BENIN.

OND. ACCOUNTING 2010-2012

 ${\sf MOSHOOD\ ABIOLA\ POLYTHECNIC}.$ 

ABEOKUTA, OGUN STATE.

### **PROFESSIONAL CERTIFICATION**

Financial Modeling & Valua; on Analyst (FMVA)® CFI (in progress)

Accoun;ng Fundamentals

CFI
Introduc;on to Business Intelligence

CFI
Database and SQL for Data Science with Python

IBM

Frontend Development TECH 365

### **INTEREST AND ACTIVITIES HOBBIES**

Learning Reading Networking Traveling Sports